learnearnown.com 2019-05-06

# LEO

### 1\. Information About Us

Learning Enterprises Organisation Limited understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used. We respect and value the privacy of all our Members and employees and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described here, and in a way that is consistent with our obligations and your rights under the law.

Learning Enterprises Organisation Ltd is a limited company, registered in England under the company number 7978520 Registered address: 112 Battle Barns, Preston Crowmarsh, Wallingford, Oxfordshire, OX10 6SL.

We are a proud member of the Direct Selling Association in the United Kingdom, Ireland, Pakistan and the United Arab Emirates.

### 2\. What Does This Notice Cover?

This Privacy Information explains how we use your personal data: how it is collected, how it is held, and how it is processed. It also explains your rights under the law relating to your personal data. The current version of the privacy policy is Version 2.0.

### 3\. What is Personal Data?

Personal data is defined by the General Data Protection Regulation (EU Regulation 2016/679) (the "GDPR") as 'any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier'.

Personal data is, in simpler terms, any information about you that enables you to be identified. Personal data covers obvious information such as your name and contact details, but it also covers less obvious information such as identification numbers, electronic location data, and other online identifiers.

The personal data that we use is set out below.

### 4\. What Are My Rights?

Under the GDPR, you have the following rights, which we will always work to uphold:

  * The right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data. This Privacy Notice should tell you everything you need to know, but you can always contact us to find out more or to ask any questions using the details at the end of this document.
  * The right to access the personal data we hold about you.
  * The right to have your personal data rectified if any of your personal data held by us is inaccurate or incomplete. Please contact us using the details at the end of this document to find out more.
  * The right to be forgotten, i.e. the right to ask us to delete or otherwise dispose of any of your personal data that we have. Please contact us using the details at the end of this document to find out more.
  * The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data.
  * The right to object to us using your personal data for a particular purpose or purposes.
  * The right to data portability. This means that, if you have provided personal data to us directly, we are using it with your consent or for the performance of a contract, and that data is processed using automated means, you can ask us for a copy of that personal data to re-use with another service or business in many cases.
  * Rights relating to automated decision-making and profiling. We do not use your personal data in this way.

For more information about our use of your personal data or exercising your rights as outlined above, please contact us using the details provided at the end of this document.

Further information about your rights can also be obtained from the Information Commissioner's Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.

If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office.

### 5\. What Personal Data Do You Collect?

Under the GDPR, we must always have a lawful basis for using personal data. This may be because the data is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to our use of your personal data, or because it is in our legitimate business interests to use it. Your personal data will be used for the following purposes:

**Information you give us.** You may give us information about you by filling in forms on the site or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. We will use this information:

  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;
  * to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;
  * to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you. If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.
  * to notify you about changes to our service;
  * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * We have a legal obligations under the money laundering regulations 2007 to identify and verify its customers and perform ongoing monitoring on customer data. As part of customer identification ("KYC") procedures we collect personal information and in some cases sensitive personal information, such as phone numbers, e-mail addresses and financial details, along with identification information such as date of birth, residential address and nationality. We may also hold personal information (including sensitive personal information) obtained through publicly available sources such as credit agencies, media publications and company registries.
  * In the interests of fraud prevention and the prevention of financial crime(s) your customer identification data will be shared with third parties who perform monitoring services on behalf of Learning Enterprises Organisation Limited.
  * Your personal data will only be shared in accordance with data protection laws were deemed necessary and where third parties are providing services to us as part of our ongoing services and in order to satisfy our legal and regulatory obligations and/or provision of our ongoing services to clients.

**Information we receive from other sources.** We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may us this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

You will not be sent any unlawful marketing or spam. We will always work to fully protect your rights and comply with our obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, and you will always have the opportunity to opt-out.

### 6\. How Long Will You Keep My Personal Data?

We will not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. Your personal data will therefore be kept for the following periods (or, where there is no fixed period, the following factors will be used to determine how long it is kept):

  * Know Your Customer (KYC) 60 days
  * Membership Details for the life of membership for Business needs
  * Finance Data under Legal Obligations
  * Product Supply Information 6 months
  * Data for the use of HR under Legal Obligations

### 7\. How and Where Do You Store or Transfer My Personal Data?

We may store or transfer some or all of your personal data in countries that are not part of the European Economic Area (the "EEA" consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein). These are known as "third countries" and may not have data protection laws that are as strong as those in the UK and/or the EEA. This means that we will take additional steps in order to ensure that your personal data is treated just as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the GDPR as follows.

We share your data within the group of companies of which we are a part. Where this involves the transfer of personal data outside the EEA, our group ensures that personal data is protected by requiring all companies within the group to follow the same rules with respect to personal data usage. These are known as "binding corporate rules". More information on binding corporate rules is available from the European Commission.

Where we transfer your data to a third party based in the US, this may be protected if they are part of the EU-US Privacy Shield. This requires that third party to provide data protection to standards similar levels of data protection to those in Europe. More information is available from the European Commission.

Please contact us using the details provided at the end of this document for further information about the particular data protection mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data to a third country.

### 8\. Do You Share My Personal Data?

We may share your personal data with other companies in our group so that you can access all available products as part of your membership.

We may sometimes contract third parties to supply products and services to you on our behalf. These may include payment processing, delivery, and marketing. In some cases, those third parties may require access to some or all of your personal data that we hold.

If any of your personal data is required by a third party, as described above, we will take steps to ensure that your personal data is handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, our obligations, and the third party's obligations under the law, as described above in Part 7.

If any personal data is transferred outside of the EEA, we will take suitable steps in order to ensure that your personal data is treated just as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the GDPR, as explained in Part 7.

In some limited circumstances, we may be legally required to share certain personal data, which might include yours, if we are involved in legal proceedings or complying with legal obligations, a court order, or the instructions of a government authority.

### 9\. How Can I Access My Personal Data?

If you want to know what personal data we have about you, you can ask us for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a "subject access request".

All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent to the email or postal addresses shown at the end of this document. To make this as easy as possible for you, a Subject Access Request Form is available for you to use on request.

You do not have to use this form, but it is the easiest way to tell us everything we need to know to respond to your request as quickly as possible.

There is not normally any charge for a subject access request. If your request is 'manifestly unfounded or excessive' (for example, if you make repetitive requests) a fee may be charged to cover our administrative costs in responding.

We will respond to your subject access request within 28 days (less than one month), in any case, not more than one month of receiving it. Normally, we aim to provide a complete response, including a copy of your personal data within that time. In some cases, however, particularly if your request is more complex, more time may be required up to a maximum of three months from the date we receive your request. You will be kept fully informed of our progress.

### 10\. How Do I Contact You?

To contact us about anything to do with your personal data and data protection, including to make a subject access request, please use the following details (for the attention of the Data Protection Officer):

Email address: [Chiefprivacyofficer@welcometoleo.com](mailto:Chiefprivacyofficer@welcometoleo.com).

Telephone number: +44 01491824970,

Postal Address: 98 Battle Barns., Preston Crowmarsh, Wallingford, Oxfordshire, OX10 6SL

### 11\. Changes to this Privacy Notice

We may change this Privacy Notice from time to time. This may be necessary, for example, if the law changes, or if we change our business in a way that affects personal data protection.

Any changes will be made available via our website and to members
